# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hey guys this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In today's video I'm gonna share with you a homely dish
# 可乐鸡翅
Cola Chicken Wings
# 首先我们准备适量的冰冻鸡翅
First, prepare frozen chicken wings as many as you need
# 解冻之后加入生抽酱油抓拌均匀腌制10分钟备用
De-frost them and season with light soy sauce for 10 minutes
# 不喜欢冰冻鸡翅的同学可以换成鸡腿
You can use fresh chicken thighs if you prefer
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, let's get ready the side ingredients
# 准备生姜1块切成姜片备用
Prepare one lump of ginger and cut into slices
# 准备小葱几根挽成结备用
Some scallions and make a knot
# 最后在碗中加入适量的可乐备用（约600克）
At last, cola to taste (about 600g) into the bowl
# 下一步开始制作
Now let's start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的植物油烧热
Next, add a proper amount of veggie oil and heat it up
# 油温5成热之后加入切好的姜片爆香
When the oil is heated up to about 150 °C, put in the ginger slices, and stir-fry until aromatic
# 姜片爆香之后将腌制好的鸡翅依次下锅
Now put in the chicken wings
# 加姜片爆锅的目的是增香和防止鸡翅粘锅
The ginger slices are for the aroma, also to prevent the wings from sticking to the wok
# 然后转小火将鸡翅煎6分钟
Fry the chicken wings for 6 minutes in low heat
# 这一步的目的是将鸡翅两面煎至金黄皮脆
So that both sides of chicken wings are golden and crispy
# 中途的时候将其翻面过来继续煎
Remember to flip them when frying
# 6分钟之后将准备好的可乐下锅开大火烧开
After 6 minutes, pour in the cola and boil it in high heat
# 再加入准备好的小葱结
Also put in the prepared scallion knot
# 大火烧开之后撇去浮沫
Discard the foam when boiling
# 同学们由于可乐本身会有泡沫
Notice the drizzling foam from cola itself
# 只需将锅中黑色的浮沫去掉即可
So you just need to remove the black foam
# 然后开始调味
Next is seasoning
# 锅中加入白糖10克
Add 10g of sugar
# 加入少许食用盐调咸味
A bit of salt
# 加入生抽酱油3克调鲜味
3g of light soy sauce for the salt and umami taste
# 然后再加入少许糖色
Some sugar colour
# 没有糖色的同学可以用老抽代替
Use dark soy sauce if you don't have sugar colour
# 调好味之后转小火烧15分钟
After seasoning, braise for 15 minutes in low heat
# 中途再把小葱和姜片捞出丢弃不用
Discard the scallions and ginger slices when braising
# 烧至15分钟之后开始转中火收汁
After 15 minutes, turn to middle heat to thicken the sauce
# 当汁水收汁粘稠可以挂上鸡翅的时候即可出锅摆盘
When the sauce is thick enough to stick to the chicken wings, the dish is almost finished
# 一道非常美味的可乐鸡翅就制作完成
Now, the very delicious Cola Chicken Wings is ready to serve!
# 下面开始技术总结
Here are some tips
# 第一，大量的鸡翅只有冻货，同学们也可以用新鲜的鸡腿代替
Tip 1: Because of the number of chicken wings we need, we can only use frozen products. You can replace them with fresh chicken thighs
# 第二，腌制鸡翅不需要加盐，只需用少许生抽酱油即可
Tip 2: Salt is not required in seasoning. You only need a little soy sauce
# 第三，煎鸡翅可以用生姜做铺垫，否则容易粘锅
Tip 3: Using ginger slices as a bottom layer while frying chicken wings can prevent the wings from sticking to the wok
# 第四，收汁不可用大火，否则味道容易变苦
Tip 4: When thickening the sauce, the heat should be kept in low or middle, otherwise the taste could get bitter
# 可乐鸡翅的技术总结完毕
That's all for the tips!